Krzysztof Radomski





About

I am a product engineer with over seven years of expertise in building user interfaces. My passion lies in web technologies, and I am dedicated to enhancing user and team experiences through my work. While I specialize in React.js, my experience spans the entire software development lifecycle, from meticulous craftsmanship to architecture and leadership.

Work Experience

Netigate remote

Frontend Developer → Frontend Tech Lead

Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, PrimeReact, Tailwind, Storybook, Playwright, Azure

- Migrated a customer app from jQuery to React; co-created a modern React app template now used in 12 production applications
- Co-authored 2 component libraries and platform localization; created a custom Eslint plugin, 2 embedded widgets, numerous documents, reviews, proof of concepts and more
- Author of the microfrontend architecture powering netigate
- io/ex platform
- I remove obstacles and help others succeed in all their frontend endeavors

Neofonie hybrid

2019 - 2021

2021 -

Frontend Software Engineer

Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Material UI, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Freemarker, Jest

- Implemented support for numerous devices, including smart bulbs, blinds and shutters, cameras, alarm system and fixed numerous bugs in the browser client for Radamaher home automation system; later served as a part time reviewer and consultant on this project
- Created numerous widgets, layouts and ui features for the new website for the Weser Kurier regional newspaper
- Implemented numerous UI features, including infinite scroll lists, map support, css optimizations, file upload handling, and wrote tests to bring the UI code coverage to over 75% for a new consultant platform for HRS

Skillbill (now: Finx) remote

2019 - 2019

React Developer

React, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Jest, Formik, Redux, Material UI

• Conract work on maintenance and new features development on a realtime to voting app, and an insurance manager helper PWA app

GogoApps on-site

2018 - 2019

JavaScript Developer

React, Redux, Chartjs, Threejs, Javascript, Gatbsy, Typescript, Redux, React Testing Library

- I was the main frontend developer on a cryptocurrency news portal, and it was my first commercial React project
- Later, I joined a team that worked on a series of educational applications for Arizona State University, where I contributed alot of components and UI features
- Also worked on company's website and few smaller projects and proof of concepts

QuarticON on-site

2017 - 2018

Junior JavaScript Developer → Tech Support -> Tech Support Lead

JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, AWS

- Implemented the main product recommendation engine for over 10 e-commerce platforms, also worked on data scrapping and at a verification
- Later, I transitioned into a tech support role

self-employed hybrid

2010 - 2017

linguist

Polish, English, German

• Self-employed linguist, translator and ESL teacher

Education

University of Warsaw

2004 - 2009

Master's Degree in English Studies

Skills



Other projects

ADP •

As the frontend architect consulant, I set the foundations for taking a Windows native payroll app to the browser. It has been a success and the project is scheduled for production.

2023/2024 Side Project

React TypeScript Kendo UI

Redux

FAIRYTAILS •

A fairy tale generator that uses AI to create children stories from simple prompts. Paused due to unresolved issues securing a truly consistent image generation model, and lack of time.

2024/paused Pet Project

TypeScript Nextjs Tailwind

Deno Postgres Open AI

Teatr Wybrzeże •

New website for a Polish theatre. I created parts of the frontend, and most of the backend. Also, I was responsible for all devops work, and third party integrations like analytics, alerting, image hosting and mailing.

2022/2023 Side Project

Next.js Strapi Node.js

Tailwind

math4kids •

A simple PWA and also a native app to play around with mathemathical operations. It was a fun project to learn React Native.

2021 Pet Project React React Native TypeScript

Storybook Vitest Addon •

Developed a custom Storybook plugin to display unit test results in a the Storybook's component tab.

2021 Pet project React
Storybook Vite.js

Tanks! •

A browser version of an old Nintendo game, Battle City. My own take at the classic arcade game, featuring realtime multiplayer using websockets.

2019 Pet Project Javascript
Socket.io CSS HTML
Firebase

Compadre •

A random name generator, my first open source project.

2018 Pet Project JavaScript